Hello everyone, welcome to our channel
IPL Manoj. Today we will talk on another topic
which is also a big issue. For a
long time now, we have been shifting towards online. In
such a situation, people have to
purchase insurance online from companies or brokers. So, I
want to know from you whether a
common man should buy insurance through online insurance form
or should he
buy insurance in the traditional way from his nearby advisor. The
issue that you have raised or
we are sitting here today just for discussion is really a very important one on
which many
different types of discussions take place. So,
I will give my opinion on this
with samblogics whether we should buy online
or we should buy offline, should we buy through an agent? So what
if I talk about before 2000,
many insurance companies have come up and
as any sector grows, many
job opportunities and
earning opportunities come in it. Similarly, as the
companies grew, they expanded their business.
For this, an agent was needed and
if I talk about it from 2010 till 2012, initially
this was prevalent, mostly
things were sold offline, but since the
advent of Policy Bazaar, after the advent of which market,
people got some awareness that one can also go online.
Policer, as a cricketer, has graphed the market very well,
now we will bring a lot of money in it, a
lot has happened and the agent
community has also benefited from this. Look at
how people are seeing Policy Bazaar,
see that for ₹500 or ₹600 you get insurance of one crore,
now even those who do not have an insurance will
think once, let's see
what
you have because today what would happen on time, it was not that much,
after the arrival of Jio, everyone has a mobile in their hand
and internet in their hand, you have to go there, the
internet charges were
350, okay, so it was not that much on time,
still because those ads used to
run on TV, people would watch them on TV,
ask their nearest agent and ultimately it was
explained to them that  Yes, this is a minimum
insurance for the next 18 years, for example, and it was mentioned on a monthly basis,
and that is what happens now. It was the same now,
but there was a little manipulation of showing it, so that
people find the
offer attractive to different people and people
think of buying it. So wherever
people from the corporate world are, they will
reach there, but it will remain to be seen that
both things grow with time. There is an
agent community and if I
talk about greater, then aggregators have also grown.
Earlier, there used to be only one policy market.
Today, if I talk about which
market is like Polisex, there are
about 10-12 more aggregators like this. Many
brokers have come into it,
so the industry is growing, but we
cannot say that only digital is
growing, the rest is growing conventionally as well.
Now, what is the difference in that,
and if you want to buy insurance, then
from where should you buy it? Look, it depends if
you feel that you can handle all the work yourself,
you have enough time.
By time, I mean tomorrow.  When a claim
comes, you can directly
talk to the customer care executive through customer care
or if you take it in, your
family, your wife or your father
can talk to the customer care executive and
especially I am talking about health insurance, then
in that case you should
take it online because there you get 5%
discount mostly in many plans, so if
you think that 5% is that much work, then by
saving that 5% you will manage the rest of the things yourself
and not only the coordination of the claim, there is
also pre-post.
Pre-post means when
you are admitted, there are expenses before
and expenses after discharge, plus
you feel that you can read all the conditions yourself and
see
what was covered in the room rent, conditions change from
time to time, if the plan changes, if you
feel that you can stay updated on everything then
online is the best because
you neither have to ask nor tell anyone,
select your insurance yourself, all the
plans as per your wish  Read it carefully, let me analyse it a bit, if
you take it, then for the last 9 years I have been a
manager in the company and have performed many of my duties, then there is a
place where
after taking actual health insurance, if the customer needs it then he does
not even know that here at least
I will need my agent or advisor
and there he can get treatment from the advisor in a
better way and not
in the customer care because there every time
a new person is picking up your call,
Manoj ji you have asked a very important question
and this is very close to my heart,
what happens is that insurance is never
such a thing which can be
shorted through customer care, if I talk about car
insurance then maybe some
things get shorted there but there
I have seen that the agents have a lot of
things which I mean you must have noticed that it is
necessary, when in their time also the government had
kept it in the list of necessary things,
such a thing is if you ever get fever, that is a
common thing, cold coffee,
when the dengue season had come, I was looking at the
claims of many days  If it has come, then do people
think that after 2 years or 3 years the policy will
not be rejected, this means it is the
thought process of people, but what I have
seen now, in the last two months of the loan season, it is
around 40% and I am
giving a big number, accurate means 40 is a very big
number, but because I am handling a big
portfolio, so I have taken
feedback from not only where I work but also from my very good friends, so I have given around 40%, the
claim reasoning is that it was not like this, the
company was wrong, the company was not
wrong anywhere, then
why are there results there, so whenever a loan
claim comes, the customer gets worried
because there is a rate of falling platelets, there is a
risk of death, now looking at all those things
from the customer's point of view,
brother, he needs it, if someone has
run the policy for 5-6 years, he will need it today, he will get the
claim, yes, I will also take advance in this,
in every village there will be such a time where perhaps the
platelet count will be low for him.  It was ₹70000 but due to some reason
he could not survive, so people start feeling scared
that as soon as the number of patients goes below one lakh, then they should get
admitted in the hospital. You are absolutely
right Manoj ji, but I will
continue the earlier point a little bit, so what happens is that
whenever someone feels and this is
training brother, if today I will
look into my safety in insurance, but here
perhaps there was no need for admission, still the
hospital admitted him, whenever any
such
disease spreads which means it impacts a large population,
some guidelines are issued in that case,
Iqama and AIIMS had
issued guidelines that there should be a particular spo2 level,
he should have these symptoms,
his fear should be this much, so if they follow it and
admit everyone, then beds will
not be available and these conditions are at the
time of denial, but what happened
in this case is that some hospitals had shown the
bed capacity which was normal earlier with someone, so
now that deal was done,  If the
beds are allotted, then the hospital does
not need much.
Many times the hospital has to admit patients unwillingly, so the
company will never give a clean chit in those cases
where a particular parameter is
not met. If you have
an agent and you keep telling him that I have a
fever of 102, I have a fever of 1, but the platelets are
not falling yet, then he
can make you aware on time that sir, look there are some
certain parameters,
why should the platelets be less than approximately 1 lakh,
Covid-Pos - this should be your
positive report, along with
dehydration, so there are some
parameters which they know about
because one or two claims are going on, the
results are available as per the
time guidelines,
but even if the same is done online, then
in that case you have no option but to go and get
admitted, the company has already
declined the claim as per the standard rules issued by ICMR and AIIMS,
and there the customer himself who is
insured inside, the family court is
doing the net, ultimately they pay and  D
paying games so the hospital has already made money
and the customer did not need to get
admitted but because he was afraid, so
because of the fear they will
believe me, even inside that means the
normal bill is 40 paise to ₹40 thousand, it depends,
if I talk about the moped of patience, the one who
discharges in it was
50 to 60 depending on the city to city
and hospital to hospital,
so it is good there
around 60-70, but here the cases are there,
so I have seen that the bills go up quite high
which are around three to four lakhs
and recently my father was admitted
and his bill was around ₹3.5 lakh, the
claim for admission was for 11 days,
so the companies majorly check whether there is
addiction etc. and there are many
parameters after asking, only
being positive, having fever
and admission of scope means they will not
give one in that, so if this thing is known  Initially, you
tell the customer that he normally takes his treatment at home to
maintain fever, that is, after
checking vitals, he
takes whatever medicines are recommended to him and gets cured at home. So,
any such treatment which can be
managed in OPD, the insurance
company cannot claim for it, so there are
some other things like that, now its main lo
pre post, in today's time, the
industries which say are 65% are
cashless,
you go home, then they take care of themselves, they
never take time to
go and submit the bill to the company, fill the claim form,
courier it, scan it, every
company has a different process, at some places the
physical copy is scanned, at some places
you have to go to the branch on that day, then a
claim form is also made, so people feel
headed that in today's time,
money is not a problem for everyone, time is a
problem, there is no time,
if you
leave it on Sunday, then
ultimately that 5% which we have
saved there, then in return of that, I don't know how much, so
one time  It makes you aware that
these things will be covered by the agent and these will not be covered
in the pre-post. It helps you in the claim.
Thirdly, in almost every policy that I am
making today, there is
a parameter of health checkup. Health checkup is a
parameter that you are
given a health benefit. To
claim it, there will be a process in every company.
Some companies provide cashless health checkup, some provide
cashless health checkup, some provide both. Each
company has its own process for
providing health checkup
and some provide cashless health checkup, some provide
both. So,
where cashless is available, mostly
you have to fix it through customer care.
In case of reimbursement, you can
go to any centre of your choice or
any hospital and get the test done and get
it cleaned. So,
in that case, where you have to go to any of these two
things and an agent is needed,
why is it needed because sometimes the time is long, there is a
separate
helpline which is
called an agent.  The agent will first talk to the agent,
connect him to the team, tell him all your
policy number, line up everything for you and
then take you on the line, this
saves your time. Secondly, if that is
not possible on the phone many times, then they take an email from you,
then a ticket is released
and you get a call and your schedule is done.
But if you are
not comfortable in the company's labs,
then in that case you can get the test done as per your choice,
but they have to be cleaned again.
For the claim, you have to
send the physical documents to the company's Adobe. The
claim form is filled together.
Now, because you may not have ever filled the claim form, for
many people, there is a
big handicap for them, they keep it at
5000 or 10 thousand, whatever the limit is, or
leave the limit of 10000, so you suffer a
loss there too. If there
is an agent there, then the agent takes the pen from him, that is, the
agent thinks of giving him the service
so that if he provides you a service, then tomorrow
he will get a referral, so ultimately when you do a  If you
buy insurance through insurance, then
he remains connected to you, that is, he
always has a greed that if I
serve a customer today, then tomorrow in the future
I will get references from all his relatives, his friends, so in
such a situation, whenever your
claim's turn comes, the first thing that happens to the agent is that it has been
seen many times
that there are delays due to claims, the
final approval of the company is as
tight as 4 hours, the turn-on time, so
where there is an agent, it is not above the agent but the entire area, the
agent has a manager,
above the manager there is a branch manager,
above him there is an area head,
above him there is a cluster head, above him there is
a regional head, above him there is a zonal head,
above him there is an agency head, so
it is the entire area, now if
something is going wrong somewhere, the scene is not working, then that person
highlights the case to his supervisor, then it does not subside in 10-20 minutes,
he super hits it and the
matter is escalated to one, two or three levels.
But if you have done it directly,
you do not have any option except
customer care, every time you call, you will have to
repeat the story and report
and every time you will get a new person and they
only say one thing that sir, do you do CR
checking, it does
not matter to them, no matter how many times you
tell them, it is going on as much as you want, it will
not matter to them at all, but here, like if someone has taken
insurance for his customer, while doing it, he will feel
that I am going to take a
future reference from
him because every customer who goes does
not join just one, he has already added two or four punches, so
he knows that
friend, four more punches of mine will go, somewhere the
agent knows that he is going to get a claim, there is just some
skill confusion, if the
documentation is
incomplete then maybe
after completing it, he will get the claim, Exactly, so what
happens is normal, whenever there is cashless
or reimbursement, companies sometimes
apply retirement and that retirement sends an
email to the agent and the customer's claim is received.
Now, where the agent is not in the loop,
for example, the case has not been taken through the agent,
such technical terms are
written in the mail like please provide
ICB papers, first diagnosis letter and
previous medical reports.
Till the previous medical reports, we understand it, but
most people do not even know about ICP papers.
Such papers also mean
endocrine papers. Apart from that,
what is a first diagnosis letter? It is
simple to understand that I am the first
diagnosis letter, but
understand the entire story of when I was diagnosed,
what did I show to this doctor, there are
such important things which the agent
helps you from time to time. The email that is
triggered by you triggers the agent.
Many times it is seen that
people in other areas have taken insurance or someone called them, they
took the picture of the market person through the phone, their
email ID is
not updated, so there is no conversation or communication.
Nowadays, if you
go to a medical hospital, you have to make the call yourself. It is
such that even that form is not there.  I can do it
and I go in a very fast manner, Rajveer
ji, it takes me half an hour because I have to
sign the claim form, I have to go to the
doctor on the 34th floor, get it
written from him, I have to
give it back to the T-pay department, only then the
claim process will be going on somewhere
and here the biggest thing I talk about is
emotional connect, I can
call you at any time, even at
11 o'clock, you say, Manoj ji, this has happened,
this problem has happened with the child, where should I
take him, then he gets to
know about cashless immediately because the agents are
updated, those cards are
not available anywhere immediately, if you don't get a copy from us, they send me an
immediate WhatsApp email
because I have portals,
they can guide you immediately, there is a
specialist for this thing, there is
immunity, those 50 things help you,
but if you have done everything online
[Music] you
get a personal assistant for health insurance
who will tell you everything in detail,
whether it is about a disease  I am working on this
because whether it is about passing pre post claims or about
passing claims or if
you have free doctor's
appointment and
obviously if he has references then he will provide
you so many services,
I will add two more points in this, one which is the most
important point is that it
helps you to select a good health insurance in the beginning itself because in
today's time, being
Insurance Pathshala founder, what I have read dear, there are about
31 insurance companies which are
selling health insurance and there are about
208 plans, the active plans which have been discontinued are
different, there are 238 plans, now within those 238 plans,
which plan of which company is
providing what features, there are so many technical
terms that a single person does not
know, the agent is getting training from the company every week or every 15 days, in
this field they are well trained, in
this field they are considered specialists, that is why
always try to buy insurance from your nearest agents
because they are
always concerned about your welfare  He will think about it and
tell you a good plan because he was
told that if he did not give a good plan then
tomorrow you can port it to anywhere,
so there are 38 plans available, so
which one is mine, only my advisor will be
able to tell,
so thank you, thank you, so today's episode must have put an end
somewhere to the debate
whether we should purchase insurance online
or in the traditional way from
our Near By Advisor, thank you